hello and welcome to another lesson in
this course
today we are going to learn about what
is tosca
what are the different features of tosca
which makes it a popular automation tool
we'll look at all the different
components which form
the tosca test automation suit
and we'll also look at how tosca differs
from another popular web automation
testing tool
which is selenium
so let's start off by learning more
about tosca
in simple terms tosca is a scriptless ai
based
no code automation tool for end-to-end
test
automation so in tosca
without writing a single line of code or
script you can automate any type of
application
be it a web application a mobile
desktop application or you can also
automate
api based applications
it uses artificial intelligence and
different technologies to identify all
the elements
on your application
also it is a continuous testing platform
that delivers fast feedback for agile
and devops so you can integrate your
tosca test automation suit
with a ci cd tool like jenkins
which will deliver fast feedback for
your agile development teams
and it will also help you to integrate
your testing
with the cicd pipeline in a devops
environment
tosca allows us to design functional
automated end-to-end software test
across all layers of the enterprise
architecture
and what i mean is you can design manual
tests
automated tests api tests
and a lot more across all the layers
of your application be it the front end
back end or the api layer
it also provides real-time risk
assessment
with business focused actionable results
so what you can do with tosca is you can
do
a risk assessment so you can create your
business requirements
and then you can put a weightage on
each requirement and then they could be
linked to different test cases
and your test reports through which
you can measure the risk of all your
test cases
in a particular release
it also ensures availability of
appropriate test data
at any time so tosca uses
test data management through which it
can store
all the different test cases and the
test data
which is available at any point of time
you can either store it in the same
database
where tosca is running
or you can also set up an external
database for your test data management
tosca also helps you to simulate the
behavior
of dependent systems if they are
unavailable
during your test execution
so this is done with the help of service
virtualization
which is also provided by tosca
through which you can emulate any
particular system
and its behavior so that in case it is
not available
you can still go ahead with a test
execution
now let's look at some of the features
which tosca provides
so tosca provides you with risk based
testing
which means you can track your
requirements based on the risk weightage
also you can perform load testing on
your applications
using the tosca you can perform all the
activities
which are part of test management like
defining your requirements tracking your
requirements
performing risk analysis and a lot more
you can also manage your test data in
different
databases either external or on the same
database
you can do manual testing and also
exploratory testing which is provided by
tosca
you can also perform api testing using
the tosca
automation tool
you can do a lot of different analysis
and analytics on different data and test
cases
you can take advantage of bi
and big data while doing all of these
analysis
as i explained earlier we can do
exploratory testing
and we can also integrate tosca into a
continuous integration tool
like jenkins
we can do service virtualization which
means
even though our applications are not
available
we can still perform testing on
these applications which are emulated by
tosca
we can do impact analysis with
the risk-based testing
now let's look at some of the tosca
components
so tosca commander is the main component
which enables easy creation management
execution and analysis of the automation
test cases
then there is tosca executor which helps
us
to execute the test cases on different
test
objects there is also tosca x
scan which basically scans the
application
and saves the technical information of
all the elements
in different modules which is then used
to identify
and steer the screen items
we have also got the test repository in
tosca
which helps us to manage the test data
needed for all the test execution
now let's talk about what's the
difference between
tosca and one of the most popular
automation tools which is selenium
the first difference which you'll notice
is selenium is an open
and free tool but tosca is a licensed
and paid tool tosca is
completely codeless which means you
don't need to write any code in order to
automate any application
but in selenium it's a complete
code-based tool
right so you have to use some language
in order to write your scripts
tosca supports all types of applications
be it web
desktop or mobile but selenium supports
only web applications
there is a dedicated support team for
tosca if you come across
any issues or you require any help
but in selenium you will only
have to fall back on community support
tosca comes with inbuilt reporting and
object repository features
but there is no such feature for
reporting an object repository in
selenium webdriver
tosca is built upon model based test
automation
while selenium is a script-based test
automation right
so in selenium you have to write all the
scripts in order to execute the test
cases
but in tosca you can build different
modules
through which you can drive your
automation
tosca also supports api and load testing
but there is no such support for
selenium out of the box for api or load
testing
so these are all the differences between
tosca
and selenium so both have their own
disadvantages and advantages
and then you have to decide based on the
budget
uh the types of applications and uh
what are the skill sets of your team
members based on which
you want to decide on which automation
tool is best for your application